PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(light tapping)
（灯光轻敲）
- We've just seen the beautiful rainbows you get
- 我们已经看过了 当你用三棱镜
when you refract light with a prism.
折射光线时产生的美丽彩虹
Now let's think about how we actually perceive
现在让我们思考一下 当我们第一眼看见
the colors of the rainbow in the first place.
彩虹的色彩的时候是如何感知它的
What makes yellow look like yellow?
是什么让黄色看起来像黄色？
Inside our eyes, we have special color receptors
在我们的眼睛中 有特殊的被称为
called cones, that are sensitive to specific
视锥细胞的色彩接收器 它们对
wavelengths of light.
特定波长的光线敏感
For example, one kind of cone is most sensitive
举例来说 有种视锥细胞对
to red light, so when long wavelength light hits them,
红光最为敏感 所以当从光谱红端发出的
that is from the red end of the spectrum,
长波光撞上它们时
they respond by sending a corresponding electrical
它们就会向大脑发出相应的电信号
signal to the brain, and the magnitude of this signal
信号的强度
will depend on how much red light is present in the light.
将由光线中红光的多少来决定
Our eyes have three main kinds of color receptors.
我们的眼睛中含有三种主要的色彩接收器
One is sensitive to the longer wavelengths,
一个对长波长 也就是红光敏感
redder light, one for medium wavelengths, or greener light.
一个对中波长 也就是绿光敏感
And one for shorter wavelengths, or the bluer light.
一个对短波长 也就是蓝光敏感
The cool trick is our brain blends signals from
最棒的部分就是我们的大脑通过混合
these three receptors to represent any color.
来自这三种接收器的信号来表示任何色彩
Colored television, and computer monitors,
彩色电视和电脑显示器
borrowed this same idea of color receptors from our eyes.
从我们的眼中借鉴了色彩接收器的想法
If you zoom into a computer screen,
如果你放大电脑屏幕来看
you'll see it's made up of tiny rectangles, or pixels.
你就能看到 它是由很多被称作像素的小方块组成的
Each of which contain a red, green, and blue region.
每个小方块都含有红绿蓝三色区域
To display colors, the monitor illuminates
如果要显示颜色
these three colors accordingly.
显示器就会相应地点亮它们
To make the screen appear yellow,
若要让屏幕显示黄色
the monitor turns on only the red and
显示器就只会点亮每个像素的
green regions in each pixel.
红色和绿色区域
From far away, these blend into yellow.
离远了看 就混合出了黄色
And that's how we can digitally create any color
这就是我们如何数字化的创造颜色
using just different amounts of red, green, and blue.
仅需要不同量的红色绿色和蓝色
In our next exercise, you'll try to create a color
在下个测试中 你将尝试在你的显示器上
by mixing together different amounts of red, green,
用不同量的红绿蓝混合出
and blue on your monitor.
某种颜色
For example, to get this shade of green.
举个例子 混合出这种类型的绿色
It's interesting to note that other animals have
一个有趣的事实是
different cones in their eyes.
其他的动物眼中有不同的视锥细胞
For example, dogs only have cones that are sensitive
举个例子 狗的眼中
to yellow and blue, so red light doesn't
仅有对黄色和绿色敏感的视锥细胞
send signals to their brain at all.
所以红色不会对它们的大脑发出信号
The mantis shrimp, on the other hand,
另一方面 皮皮虾
holds the current record for the most
是当前具有最多的色彩感受器
number of color receptors in its eyes,
记录的保持者
12 different kinds.
一共具有 12 种（色彩感受器）
And scientists still don't know how
科学家依旧不知道
they're all used to perceive color.
它们时如何感受颜色的
- Voila, he is clean.
- 你瞧 它清干净了（它们自己最清楚了）
(exciting fun music)
（激昂而有趣的音乐）
- Beyond that though, there's also a certain class
- 除此之外 也有一类人
of people, they're all females, it turns out,
她们都是女性
who we call tetrachromats.
被称为四色视者
They have four different color receptors in the eye,
她们的眼中具有四种色觉感受器
whereas the vast majority of the population has three.
而普通大众只有三种
And so we think, and expect, that their ability
所以我们猜想 也希望 四色视者
to discriminate colors, to basically tell the difference
分辨颜色的能力 或者说分辨
between two very, very similar shades,
非常相近颜色
is probably much more precise for the tetrachromats.
将精确的多
I wish I was one. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
我真希望我是其中之一 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox